Inventory of the Dave Jones papers, 1906-1942
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Dave Jones papers
1906-1942
Jones, Dave.
00030
3.15 cubic feet (7 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Biography of Dave Jones
Dave Jones was a Cody, Wyoming, businessman and oil speculator. Jones arrived in Cody in 1904 from Iowa and opened the Dave Jones clothing store in Cody in 1906. The store became known for its innovative advertising and use of display cases. Jones was also a member of the Board of Directors of the Western Oil and Gas Company of Cody, Wyoming.
Scope and Content
Collection contains information relating to Jones' clothing store and the Western Oil and Gas Company. The collection includes correspondence (1928-1937) regarding Jones' store; ledgers (1906-1942) dealing with sales, inventories and expense accounts; catalogs of Jones' store (1938); newsclippings and advertisements of the store (1936-1942); and a manuscript by Jones in 1905 about his trip to Yellowstone National Park. The collection also includes Western Oil and Gas Company agreements and contracts (1908-1921); stock certificates (1918-1920); correspondence (1908-1925); and Board of Directors minutes of meetings (1908-1922).
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Dave Jones at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The material was received from the estate of Dave Jones in September 1946
Access Terms
Western Oil and Gas Company.; Advertising -- Wyoming -- Cody.; Clothing and dress -- Wyoming -- Cody.; Retail trade -- Wyoming -- Cody.; Petroleum industry and trade -- Wyoming -- Cody.; Cody (Wyo.) -- History.; Ledgers.; Minutes.; Catalogs, commercial.; Stock certificates.; Businessmen.;; Dave Jones Clothing Store.
Business, Industry, Labor, and Commerce; Retail Trade; Mines and Mineral Resources; City and Town Life; Wyoming
Container List
- Bank Books: Dave Jones' Account with the Shosone National Bank. Cody, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - Book #1, February 3, 1931--November 1, 1934 (Box 6)
  - Book #2, November 2, 1931-January 31, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Book #3, February 1938-January 31, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Book #4, February 1942-March 31, 1943 (Box 6)
- Broadsides, Handbills, and Leaflets: Advertising the Dave Jones Clothing Store., Cody, Wyoming (23 items) (Box 1)
- Correspondence: (Box 1)
  - To: Mrs. Mary Jester Allen. From: H.F. McLaury, June 18, 1928 (Box 1)
  - To: Mrs. Mary Jester Allen. From H. F. McLaury, August 8, 1928 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: George Lawrence Company, March 17, 1932 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: Thomas H. Mullen, August 31, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: Walter Fanning, September 3, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From E.C. Pfeffor, September 2, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: B.M. Hill. From: Dave Jones, September 3, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: B. Harold Miller, September 3, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From E.R. Richer, September 9, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: E.R. Richer, September 18, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Allan Seinsheimer. From Dave Jones, November 10, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: Allan Sinsheimer, November 16, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: E.R. Richer, November 19, 1936 (Box 1)
  - To: Dave Jones. From: E.R Richer, June 25, 1937 (Box 1)
- Data on Tourism (Yellowstone National Park Statistics and Information Releases): (Box 1)
  - "Yellowstone Park, Wyoming October 1925 " (Box 1)
  - "1925 Comparative Travel Figures With 1924 and 1923 Season to August 31st, inclusive" (Box 1)
  - "Yellowstone Park, Wyoming, October, 1924" (Box 1)
  - "1924 Comparative Travel Figures With 1923 and 1922 Season to August 31st, Inclusive" (Box 1)
  - "Yellowstone 1926 Season Smashes All Travel Records" (Box 1)
  - "1926 Comparative Travel Figures With 1925 and 1924 Season to July 31st, Inclusive" (Box 1)
  - "Memorandum Regarding Travel Via the Cody Gateway in 1928" (Box 1)
  - Maps (3 identical) of Yellowstone Park and Table of Distances (1928) (Box 1)
- Decals: Advertising Justin Boots (9) (Box 1)
- Journals (All of the financial type, and pertaining mainly to the Dave Jones Clothing Store): (Box 2)
  - No. 1: Sales and Other Entries, 1899-1923 (Box 2)
  - No. 2: Sales Entries, February 1908-January 2, 1912 (Box 2)
  - No 3: Sales Entries, December 24, 1919-February 1925 (Box 2)
  - No. 4: Sales Entries, February 1923-February 1924 (Box 2)
  - No 5: Invoice and Inventory Entries, February 1936- February 1942 (Box 2)
- Ledgers: (Box 2)
  - Ledger, 1900-1905 (Box 2)
  - Ledger entitled " David Jones, Veo, Iowa, No. 585 Ledger"; Loose items within include: Scientific American Map of Cuba, "From December 28, 1890-JOURNAL". Furnance Fire-building directions, Chas. W. Gates, Oct. 28, 1913 acct. sheet, Receipt December 13, 1900 by J.M. Jones, December 28, 1890, October 28, 1913, and December 13, 1900 (Box Oversized)
  - Day-book (ledger), February 3, 1909-December 26, 1913 (Box Oversized)
  - Expense Account, June 1, 1912-February 29, 1920 (Box Oversized)
  - Expense Account, February 1920-February 1925 (Box Oversized)
  - Transfer Sheets, General Ledger and Accts. Payable (Alphabetical subject arrangement), circa 1925-circa 1930 (Box 3)
  - General Ledger (Alphabetical subject arrangment to include the following: Accounts (General), Assets, Liabilities, Revenues, Expenses, Payable accounts), 1925-1934 (Box 3)
  - Sales Distribution for the Month of _____, Dave Jones, Cody Wyoming, February 1925-January 1928 (Box 4)
- Order Books (Fitting Charts and Order Forms for Clothing Store): (Box 5)
  - Dave Jones, Cody, Wyoming, March 1909 to August 11, 1911 (Box 5)
  - Dave Jones, Cody, Wyoming, March 1907- May 16, 1908 (Box 5)
- Pamphlets, Brochures, and Leaflets pertaining to the Tourist Attractions of the Cody-Yellowstone Park, Wyoming area and to other areas: (Box 6)
  - Aldrich Lodge, Ishawooa, Wyoming (2) (Box 6)
  - Beartooth Absaroka & Shoshone National Forest Vacation Region, 1926 (Box 6)
  - Big Horn Basin, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - Big Horn Hot Springs, Thermopolis, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - The Buffalo Bill Country Calls You (Box 6)
  - The Cody Stampede, Cody, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - The Cody Road, to Yellowstone Park (Box 6)
  - Custer Battlefield HiWay (Box 6)
  - The Dalles and Dufur, Oregon (Box 6)
  - Dude Ranches in the Big Horn Mountains (Box 6)
  - The Elbud Ranch for Boys (C158-wy) (Box 6)
  - Festival of Mountain and Plain and State Fair (Box 6)
  - Holm Lodge (Box 6)
  - Land of the Shining Mountain (Billings Gazette Supplement) (Box 6)
  - Medford Rogue River Valley (Box 6)
  - The National Park-to-Park Highway (Box 6)
  - Old Oregon Trail Guidebook (2) (Box 6)
  - Pacific Coast to Chicago via Yellowstone National Park (Box 6)
  - The Pacific Northwest (Box 6)
  - Picturesque Colorado (Box 6)
  - Ranch Life in the Buffalo Bill Country (5 copies of 3 editions) (Box 6)
  - Richard Ranch, Cody, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - See Yellowstone Park (Box 6)
  - Scenic Idaho (Box 6)
  - The Snyder Ranch, Ishawooa, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - Walla Walla Valley, Washington (Box 6)
  - The Warner-Gage Pack Trip from Cody, Wyoming (Box 6)
  - Wyoming Worth Knowing (Box 6)
  - The Yakima Valley (Box 6)
  - Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming, 1924 (Department of Interior publication of rules and regulations) (Box 6)
  - Yellowstone National Park, Wyoming 1925 (Deparment of Interior publication of rules and regulations) (Box 6)
  - Yellowstone Park Camps (Box 6)
- Photos: (Box vertical files)
  - Bald Ridge (Folder B19r)
  - Bear (Folder B38)
  - Big Creek (Folder B48c)
  - Bridge (unidentified) (Folder B764u)
  - Buffalo Bill Stage Coach (Folder B-C64w)
  - Buffalo Bill Museum (2) (Folder B-C64wm)
  - Buffalo Bill and Daughter (Folder B-C64w)
  - Buffalo (Folder B-855)
  - Capitol, Cheyenne Wyoming (Folder W99-cap)
  - Clock Tower and Goose (Folder C621t&G)
  - Cody Ranch (T.E. Ranch) (Folder B-C64w)
  - Crow Indians (2) (Folder C88)
  - Coyote (Folder C8391)
  - Dam (unidentified) (Folder D1987u)
  - Dead Indian Hill (Folder B482)
  - Dude Ranch, Cody, Wyo. (Folder D86)
  - Elk (Folder EL5)
  - Fish (trout) (Folder F53)
  - Holy City, Wyo. (Folder H7473c)
  - "Hoodoo Rocks" (Folder R595)
  - "Laughing Pig" (Folder R-5959-Lp)
  - Marble Mountain (2) (Folder M328m)
  - Painter Ranch (Folder R15-pai)
  - Paradise Valley (2) (Folder P211v)
  - Palace Aids (Folder P171)
  - Powder River (Folder P87)
  - Sheep Camp (Folder Sh3ca)
  - Sheep Mountain (Folder Sh3m)
  - Spillway and Road Tunnels (Folder Sp45-rt)
  - Spring Creek (Folder Sp823-cr)
  - Stinking Water Peak (2) (Folder C64r)
  - Shoshone Canyon (Folder C64)
  - Sunlight Creek (4) (Folder B482m)
  - Sunlight Ranch (2) (Folder B482m)
  - Sunlight Valley (3) (Folder B482m)
  - Tetons, the Mighty (Folder T29m)
  - Twin Peaks (Folder T923p)
  - Wind River Canyon (6) (Folder W72c)
  - Worland Saloon (Folder W887)
  - Unindentified Photos (16) and Negatives (5) (Box 1)
- Mail Order Catalogs: (Box 1)
  - Anderson Brothers, Denver, Colorado (Box 1)
  - Dave Jones Catalog of Western Merchandise (Box 1)
  - Dave Jones Catalog For a Gentleman's Chirstmas, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Denver Dry Goods Company's "Stockmen's Supplies 1941-1942" (Box 1)
  - N. Porter Saddle & Harness Company, Pheonix, Arizona, Catalog for 1931 (Box 1)
  - White and Davis Mail Order Catalog, Spring and Summer 1932 (Box 1)
  - Various Catalog Entires Mounted on (9) loose leaf notebook pages (Box 1)
- Magazines: (Box 1)
  - National Clothier (Contains an article entitled "Friendly Copy for a Friendly Community" that featured the effective advertising techniques of Dave Jones Clothing Stores, Cody, Wyoming)., June 1937 (Box 1)
  - Saturday Evening Post (contains a feature article about life on a Wyoming dude ranch), June 10, 1939 (Box 1)
- Manuscript: "Then and Now" by Dave Jones, a brief account (5 pages) of an August, 1905, trip from Cody into Yellowstone Park--1905 being the first year the the East Entrance approach road was open to horse-drawn vehicles (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Items: (Box 1)
  - Bulletin, Frist Presbyterian Church, Cody, April 5, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Business card for The Little Shop Santa Fe, New Mexico (Box 1)
  - Cody Merchants' Credit Association, Rating Book, January 1922 (Box 1)
  - Dave Jones (business) blank stationary (Box 1)
  - Envelope, Return address being the Shoshone National Bank of Cody (Box 1)
  - Invitations to the Fire Department Banquets of 1907 and 1937 that were sponsered by Dave Jones (explanatory clippings attached) (Box 1)
  - Programs: (Box 1)
    - Dedication Service of Hoopes Memorial Chapel, March 15, 1938 (Box 1)
    - 12th Annaul Meeting, Dude Ranchers Association, Cody, Wyo., 1937 (Box 1)
    - 13th Annual Meeting, Dude Ranchers Association, Livingston Montana, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Fraternal Order of Eagles 16th Convention, Cody, Wyo., June 13-14, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Various High School and public events (programs compliments of Dave Jones) (Box 1)
  - The Spur, Meeteetse (Wyo.) High School Class of 1927 Annual (Box 1)
  - Menu (s) of the Chicago Burlington and Quincy Railroad Company, July 2 and 3, 1928 (Box 1)
- Newspaper Clippings: (Box 1)
  - Dave Jones Advertisements (188 ads, mostly undated) (Box 1)
  - "Dave Jones Store Birthday, Cody Enterprise), March 11, 1942 (Folder Dave Jones Bio File (B-J713d))
  - "Local Merchant Draw Praise of Prominent National Advertiser," Cody Enterprise, September 16, 1936 (Folder Dave Jones Bio File (B-J713d))
- Newspapers: (Box 1)
  - Cody Enterprise, May 11, 1931 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Cody Enterpise (D861ra) (pp 1-2 only), October 31, 1934 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Cody Enterpise, December 22, 1937 (Box 3 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Cody Enterpise (pp 1-2 only), December 7, 1938 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Cody Enterpise (B-D9315e) (pp 1-2 only), March 29, 1939 (Box 5 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Cody Enterpise, December 12, 1941 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Enterprise-Ad-News (Cody) (W99-t-cod), January 21, 1938 (Box 7 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Enterprise-Ad-News (Cody) (B-C64w), February 18, 1938 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Enterprise-Ad-News (Cody), April 18, 1941 (Box 9 (Unless otherwise noted))
  - Enterprise-Ad-News (Cody), December 12, 1941 (Box 1 (Unless otherwise noted))
- Notebooks: Small blank notebooks (2) distrubuted by Dave Jones Store, 1929 and 1932 (Box 6)
- Western Oil & Gas Company Materials: (Box 7)
  - Additional and Amended Location Certificates (Placer Oil Claims): (Box 7)
    - Excelsior Oil Placer Claim, February 17, 1914 (Box 7)
    - Excelsior Oil Placer Claim, January 1, 1915 (Box 7)
    - Crickett Oil Placer Claim (page 2 only), Undated (Box 7)
  - Agreements and Contracts: (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and the Torch Light Company, Ltd., November 30, 1908 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and the Shoshone Oil Company, September 13, 1911 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and the Mountain States Oil Co., December 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and Charles E. Burkhardt, December 31, 1915 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and Crystal Creek Petroleum & Refining Company, May 11, 1917 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and Charles P. Whitney, February 13, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Between Western Oil & Gas Co. and Wm. D. Livingston (Agreement not completed), January __, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Certificates for Shares of Stock: (Box 7)
    - C.F. Whitney-1000 shares of Western Oil & Gas Co., January 8, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Clyde J. Siggins- 1000 shares of Western Oil & Gas Co., January 8, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Ray B. Siggins-1000 shares of Western Oil & Gas Co., January 8, 1918 (Box 7)
    - F.O Thompson-1 share of Cody Stampede, June 19, 1920 (Box 7)
  - Certificate of Stock Register: (Box 7)
    - List issues of August 8, 1908 to March 30, 1909, August 8, 1908-March 30, 1909 (Box 7)
    - List of Stockholders and Number of Shares of Western Oil & Gas Co.., (This list is undated and loose inside the stock register) (Box 7)
  - Checkbooks (Western Oil & Gas Co.): (Box 7)
    - No.1 Checks, December 17, 1914-March 22, 1919 (Box 7)
    - No. 2 Check (remainder intact in blank form), June 16, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: L. Curtis Hinkle, August 8, 1908 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Co. From: Big Horn (Wyo.) County Clerk's Office, April 13, 1909 (Box 7)
    - To: Charles P. Whitney. From Mariner & Hoskins, April 28, 1909 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Co. From: Oil Well Supply Company, April 28, 1909 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.J Deegan, October 13, 1911 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.H. Morrison, October 22, 1912 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Frederick A. Williams, January 9, 1914 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Charles P. Whitney, April 26, 1915 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: Frederick A. Williams, July 9, 1915 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: C.E. Spangler, January 5, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: Frederick A. Williams, February 7, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Bavier C. Miller, February 9, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: F.O. Thompson, February 11, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Co. From: Mountain States Oil Company, February 21, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: J.C. Klein, March 12, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Co. From: Russell Kimball (Clipping attached), May 31, 1916 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: J.P. Brunton, February 28, 1917 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson From: J.P. Brunton (Enclosure sketch of Brunton Oil-Gas Development Co.), October 26, 1917 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Co. From: L.F. Speer, February 13, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Frank W. Mondell, Feburary 23, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: Hon. F.W. Mondell. From: F.O. Thompson, Undated (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: F.W. Mondell (telegram), February 27, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: F.W. Mondell (telegram), March 9, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.W. Mondell. From F.O. Thompson (telegram), March 9, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: F.W. Mondell, March 13, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: F.W. Mondell, March 21, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Critchell, Miller, Whitney & Barbour, Chicago, April 25, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: Register and Receiver, General Land Office (G.L.O), Lander, Wyo. From: Department of Interior, G.L.O, Washington, D.C., May 27, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Charles P. Whitney, July 1, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Robert Connaghan, July 5, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Nell & Frank (Thompson). From: Ada R. Thompson, August 12, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: J.C. Fain, September 10, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: A.W. Baker. From: F.O. Thompson, September 28, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Charles R. Whitney, October 7, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: A.W. Baker, October 11, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: "My Dear Brother" (F.O. Thompson) From: Ada R. Thompson, November 6, 1918 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Company. From: L.A. Miller, June 9, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: Register, United States Land Office, Lander, Wyoming. From: Western Oil & Gas Company, July 2, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Company. From: Robert Connaghan, July 7, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: Register, G.L.O., Lander, Wyoming. From: Western Oil & Gas Company, July 25, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: Western Oil & Gas Company. From: Robert Connaghan, July 28, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.J. Lefler, August 5, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: W.J. LeFler. From:F.O. Thompson, August 12, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: W.H. Walls. From: F.O. Thompson, August 12, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.L. Walls, August 14, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: Register, G.L.O., Lander, Wyoming. From: Western Oil & Gas Company, August 20, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Why. H. Ealey, August 31, 1920 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Wm. D. Livingston, January 5, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Wm. D. Livingston. From: F.O. Thompson, January 15, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: W.D. Livingston. From C.E. Hayden, Undated (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.D. Livingston (agreement form attached), January 20, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Charles P. Whitney (Clipping attached), February 9, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Joseph C. O'Mahony. From: F.O. Thompson, February 14, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: W.L. Walls. From: F.O. Thompson, February 16, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From W.L. Walls, February 18, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Joseph C. O'Mahoney (Bill attached for retainer fee), February 23, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: W.L. Walls. From: Joseph C. O'Mahony (Letter to F.O. Thompson of 2/23/'21 attached), February 23, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: W.L. Walls, February 26, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Joseph C. O'Mahoney. From: F.O. Thompson, April 23, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: Joseph C. O'Mahoney, April 29, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To:Western Oil & Gas Company. From: E.H. Baston, June 16, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: FO Thompson. From: W.L. Walls, July 16, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Collector of Internal Revenues, Cheyenne. From: F.O. Thompson, August 15, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: F.O. Thompson. From: A.M. Cavey, September 26, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Collector of Internal Revenues, Cheyenne. From: F.O. Thompson, September 28, 1921 (Box 7)
    - To: Joseph C. O'Mahony. From: C.E. Hayden (telegram), March 26, 1922 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: Haggard & O'Mahoney (telegram), March 27, 1922 (Box 7)
    - To: C.E. Hayden. From: Joseph C. O'Mahoney (telegram), March 29, 1922 (Box 7)
    - To: "Dear Stockholder" (Dave Jones Copy) From: I.M. McGuffey (attached stock subscription privilege certificate), July 28, 1925 (Box 7)
  - Financial Accounting Items: 52 bills, invoices, and recipts arranged chronologically, all pertaining to the Western Oil & Gas Company (Box 7)
  - Notice of Charges: "United States vs. Western Oil and Gas Company", June 11, 1918 (Box 7)
  - Notice of Location of Placer Mining Claims: W.O. & G.C. No.; Claim Name; County Claim No. (Box 7)
    - 1. Prince of Monoca. 2976, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 2. Prince Albert. 2064, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 3. Prince Arthur. 2968, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 4. Douglass. 2949, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 5. Heart Mountain. 2948, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 6. Basin. 2946, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 7. Wyoming. 2947, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 8. Bennie. 2969, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 9. Johnnie. 2963, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 10. Casper. 2956, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 11. Utah. 2957, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 12. Buffalo. 2954, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 13. Reality. 2955, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 14. Montana. 2953, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 15. Sheridan. 2952, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 16. Ideal. 2950, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 17. Cheyenne. 2951, November 11, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 18. Margarite. 2966, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 19. Mary. 2962, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 20. Beauty. 2960, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 21. Strike. 2961, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
    - 22. Slandby. 2965, November 13, 1913 (Box 7)
  - Meetings: (Minutes and Notices of various meetings of the stockholders and/or directors of the Western Oil & Gas Company) (Box 7)
    - Feburary 3, 1910 (Box 7)
    - November 4-5 1913 (Box 7)
    - May 20, 1918 (Box 7)
    - March 21, 1921 (Box 7)
    - March 28, 1922 (Box 7)
    - (2) Minutes and notes of meetings, Undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Items: (Box 7)
    - Check to Marshall Field Company, June 22, 1915 (Box 7)
    - Aetna Life Insurance Company form receipt (Box 7)
    - Death Notice-Rockwood W. Hosmer, November 4, 1916 (Box 7)
    - Business card of Joseph C. O'Mahoney, 355 Munsey Bldg. Washington, D.C. (Box 7)
    - Clipping "As Soon As Sufficient Wells Are Down" (Box 7)
    - Map, Township 53, Range 101 (with some claims marked) (Box 7)
  - Proof of Labor on Mining Claims (On work done of the Excelsior and Crickett Oil Placer Claims): (Box 7)
    - December 24, 1910 (Box 7)
    - December 31, 1911 (Box 7)
    - December 31, 1912 (Box 7)
    - December 30, 1915 (Box 7)
    - December 26, 1914 (Box 7)
    - December 12, 1918 (Box 7)
    - December 31, 1920 (Box 7)
  - Proxies, Power(s) of Attorney: 25 separate manuscript items of this sort (various individuals involved) (Box 7)
  - Quit-Claim Deeds: (Box 7)
    - From C.G. Holland to Western Oil and Gas Company, December 1913 (Box 7)
    - From B.E. Cogswell to Western Oil & Gas Company, December 9, 1913 (Box 7)
  - Record Book: Contains some of the minutes of the Western Oil & Gas Company's meetings between incorporation in May 1908 and 1918. (Minutes for 30 meetings are included, along with a list of shareholders as of May 17, 1915., May 1908 and 1918, May 17, 1915 (Box 7)
  - Statement of Account: Western Oil & Gas Company's account with the First National Bank of Cody (with 3 cancelled checks), January 29, 1916 (Box 7)
  - Tax Records:
    - Treasurer's Office, Park Country (F.O. & Mrs. Thompson), 1915 (Box 7)
    - Receipt for Income and Excess Profits for 1913, Western Oil & Gas Co. Corporation (Box 7)
    - Income and Profits Tax Return, 1919 (Box 7)
    - Corporation Income and Profits Tax Returns, 1920 (Box 7)
    - Capital Stock Tax, 1921 (Box 7)